<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE muclient>
<!-- Saved on Tuesday, December 31, 2013, 6:48 AM -->
<!-- MuClient version 4.91 -->

<!-- Plugin "tutorial_vi" generated by Plugin Wizard -->

<muclient>

<plugin
   name="tutorial_vi"
   author="Ruthgul, Jeneya"
   id="0c85b0fa3ab1503d1eb123b4"
   language="Lua"
   purpose="a set of lessons for the Materia Magica MUSHclient VI bundle"
   date_written="2013-12-31 06:47:39"
   date_modified="2017-07-22 18:52:02"
   requires="4.71"
   version="1.0"
   >

<description trim="y">

<![CDATA[

~ lessons_vi ~

A series of 1-page lessons to show the basic operation of the MUSHclient bundle for Materia Magica.


Syntax:

* lesson


Authors: Ruthgul, Jeneya, Iyara

Latest version:
http://github.com/MateriaMagicaLLC/mm-mushclient-scripts

]]>

</description>

</plugin>



<!--  Aliases  -->

<aliases>

  <alias
   match="^lesson$"
   enabled="y"
   regexp="y"
   send_to="12"
   sequence="100"
  >
  <send>show_a_page(pages["toc"])
</send>
  </alias>

  <alias
   match="^lesson[ ]+(?P&lt;num&gt;[0-9]+)$"
   enabled="y"
   regexp="y"
   send_to="12"
   sequence="100"
  >
  <send>show_a_page(pages["p%&lt;num&gt;"])
</send>
  </alias>


<!--  Plugin help  -->

  <alias
   enabled="y"
   match="^lesson(|\_vi)( |\:)help$"
   regexp="y"
   script="OnHelp"
  >
  </alias>

</aliases>




<script>

<![CDATA[

-----------------
-- plugin stuff
-----------------

function OnPluginInstall()
  Note("-- " .. GetPluginInfo(GetPluginID(), 1) .. ": type " .. GetPluginInfo(GetPluginID(), 1) .. " help to see info about this plugin --")
end


function OnHelp()
  ColourNote("silver", "black", world.GetPluginInfo(world.GetPluginID(), 3))
  Note("")
  ColourNote("silver", "black", "(this version: " .. os.date("%c", GetPluginInfo(GetPluginID(), 14)) .. ")")
end


function plugin_update_url()
  local t = {
    "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MateriaMagicaLLC/mm-mushclient-scripts/master/src/tutorial_vi.xml",
  }
  return (table.concat(t, ";"))
end


function plugin_update_aux_url()
  local t = {
    "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MateriaMagicaLLC/mm-mushclient-scripts/master/res/mm_boil.mp3,MUSH/sounds/msp",
    "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MateriaMagicaLLC/mm-mushclient-scripts/master/res/mm_stream.mp3,MUSH/sounds/msp",
  }
  return (table.concat(t, ";"))
end



-------------------
-- lesson pages
-------------------

pages = {
  ["toc"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, ToC ~

[ Table of Contents ]

lesson 0  -  Overview
lesson 1  -  Setup, Repeat command
lesson 2  -  Screen readers and SAPI
lesson 3  -  Speedwalks, Sextant readings
lesson 4  -  Captures
lesson 5  -  Example: Using speedwalk manager to locate and walk to a location, by Jeneya
lesson 6  -  The area Mapper
lesson 7  -  Example: Adding an abbreviation to a new location, by Jeneya
lesson 8  -  Aliases
lesson 9  -  Example: Making an alias to reach a captures notepad, by Jeneya
lesson 10 -  Aliases, other examples (alias to shorten mapper where, alias for hide + backstab)
lesson 11 -  Triggers
lesson 12 -  Example: Creating a simple SAPI trigger, by Jeneya
lesson 13 -  Triggers, other examples (SAPI interrupt, adding gags)
lesson 14 -  Command stacking, the Commands Sequencer
lesson 15 -  MUD Sound Protocol (MSP), Other sounds
lesson 16 -  Reading captures without changing focus
lesson 17 -  Dealing with combat spam: Sbrief
lesson 18 -  Filters for spammy commands
lesson 19 -  The keystrokes manager
lesson 20 -  Example: Adding a keystroke to stop SAPI speech, by Jeneya
lesson 21 -  Example: Adding keystrokes to read your vitals and use the check commands, by Jeneya
lesson 22 -  Example: Adding a keystroke to read captures without leaving the world window, by Jeneya
lesson 23 -  Making aliases that work with and without a target
lesson 24 -  How to install and uninstall plugins
lesson 25 -  How to update plugins
lesson 26 -  Macro keystrokes and output
lesson 27 -  Pre-installed plugins and features

]],

  ["p0"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p0 ~

[ Overview ]

This is a copy of MUSHclient v4.9x, customized to play Materia Magica.  It's meant for sight impaired players.

The package includes the client + a Materia Magica world with some pre-installed plugins: support for most screen readers, SAPI, MSP, and the BASS library, notepads for world output and channel captures, a way to read channels without moving focus from the world window, filters for certain spammy commands, a keystrokes manager, the GMCP handler, an area auto-mapper, a virtual sextant, a speedwalk manager, a commands sequencer, and a plugins updater.  Plus some other plugins that you can add if you want.


[ Note ]

If you're running Windows Vista / 7 / newer, you'll need to install Windows Help to be able to read MUSHclient's help files.

Alternatively, you can read the online documentation here:
http://www.mushclient.com/scripts/doc.php


[ Important ]

Many of the plugins and scripts in this bundle WON'T WORK PROPERLY if you run more than one character in the same MUSHclient window.

Start a new MUSHclient window for each character that you're running (as opposed to running them "tabbed" within the same MUSHclient window.)

]],


  ["p1"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p1 ~

[ Setup ]

* To make MUSHclient keep commands in the command window (eg, to help you move if you're on a laptop without a numeric keypad), go to Game, Configure, Commands (Alt + 0), and check the option Auto-repeat Commands.

* To adjust the max line length, go to Game, Configure, Output (Alt + 5), and adjust the number to the right of Wrap output at column number...  It can be a number from 20 to 500.

* In game, it is a good idea to type "set page_length 120", without the quotes, which increases the amount of lines the game will feed you at a time to the max.  So you won't be interrupted so frequently by the [C]ontinue [R]edraw [B]ack [E]xit prompt.


[ Repeat command ]

This plugin will let you repeat a command, by preceding it with a # symbol and a number.  For example, #3 look will send the look command 3 times.

]],


  ["p2"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p2 ~

[ Screen readers ]

The interface with your screen reader is handled by the MushReader plugin.

* To toggle reading on or off, type tts, or press Ctrl + Shift + F12.

* To send text to your reader's stream, type tts_note followed by the text.

* To stop what's being read, and clear the reader's stream, type tts_stop.

* To stop what's being read, clear the reader's stream, and start reading other text, type tts_interrupt followed by the text.


SAPI is handled by the Sapi_speaker plugin.

* To send text to your SAPI stream, type sapi say followed by the text.

* To stop reading the current sentence, type sapi skip.

* To stop what's being read, and clear the SAPI stream, type sapi stop.

* To stop what's being read, clear the SAPI stream, and start reading other text, type sapi interrupt followed by the text.


To see more details about these plugins, type mushreader help, and sapi help.

]],


  ["p3"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p3 ~

[ Speedwalks ]

The speedwalk_manager_p2 plugin will help you speedwalk between areas.

* To search for a city, dungeon, etc., or public ship's dock, type spdn followed by a partial area name, or public ship name.  For example, spdn sigil.  Or spdn merdraco.  If any results are found, they will be shown as an abbreviation, followed by a description.  For example, "SigN - Sigil, north".  (Note that the % symbol can be used as a wildcard.)

* To start walking to a room, type spdn followed by an abbreviation.  For example, to walk to the north gate of Sigil, we would type spdn SigN.

This command requires the GMCP mapper to be installed, and it will only start speedwalks if the destination room is connected to the current room in the map.

First, it will try to find a path from the current room to the destination room.  This process can be slow...  If a path is found, you will start speedwalking.

* Once you're speedwalking to a room, you can stop by typing mapper stop (then continue by typing mapper resume.)


[ Sextant readings ]

The faux_sextant plugin lets you check your sextant location, without needing a sextant item.  It knows your location by reading the GMCP room package instead.

* To read your current location using the default SAPI voice, type show coords.


To see more details about these plugins, type speedwalk_manager_p2 help, and faux_sextant help.

]],


  ["p4"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p4 ~

[ Captures ]

The output_functions plugin will automatically capture all activity in your world window to the output notepad.

The capture2notepads plugin will automatically capture the chosen channels (tells, ct, etc.) to notepads.

All these notepads (both output and the channels captures) will freeze when you activate them, to prevent the cursor from resetting when stuff happens in the world.

* To see the list of all open notepads, type list notepads.  The Windows menu (Alt + W) also has a list of open windows and notepads.

* To bring a given notepad to the foreground, type notepad followed by a notepad name.  For example, notepad output.

* To return focus to the world window, press Ctrl + Shift + spacebar.

* To add a channel, type capture followed by a channel type.  For example, capture say.

* To cancel a channel, type uncapture followed by a channel type.  For example, uncapture announce.


Try to clear your Output notepad regularly, by selecting all its text (Ctrl + A) then pressing Delete.  It can become cluttered pretty soon, especially when you run long speedwalks between towns, etc.


To see more details about these plugins, type output_functions help, capture2notepads help, and capture2dworld help.

]],


  ["p5"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p5 ~

[ Example: Using speedwalk manager to locate and walk to a location, by Jeneya ]

For this example we will try to find a locker in Xaventry.

1. Type "spdn xav", without the quotes.

2. Press Enter.

3. You will notice that it brings up several places in the town of Xaventry.  Listen for "Xaventry lockers" and "XavLock".

4. Press Ctrl + Alt + Spacebar to go to your Output notepad, and arrow up until you find the abbreviation for the Xaventry lockers.  Notice it is XavLock.  Select and copy it.

5. Press Ctrl + Alt + Spacebar again, to return to your world window.  Then type "spdn XavLock", without the quotes.  (Instead of typing the abbreviation, you can paste it, if you copied it in a previous step.)

6. Press Enter to go to Xaventry lockers, as long as you and Xaventry are not separated by ocean and you are in city or on a road.

This method of speedwalking is great for walking to banks, lockers, gates and quest masters.  Soon you don't have to look up the abbreviations and you will just zip around.


]],


  ["p6"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p6 ~

[ The area mapper ]

The MM_GMCP_Mapper plugin, by using the GMCP protocol, keeps track of your current room when you're not in the wilderness.

It will auto-map all towns, dungeons, and any non-wilderness areas in general.  By default, it won't map the wilds, except for the roads and piers.

We've included a partial maps database, which has most starter areas pre-mapped.

* To search for a room within your current area, type mapper find followed by a partial room name.  For example, mapper find theater.  If any results are found, they will be shown as room name, followed by room id, followed by its distance.

* To search for a room anywhere in the mapped world, type mapper where followed by a partial room name.  For example, mapper where honor.  Again, results will be shown as room name, followed by room id, followed by area name.  (Note that the % symbol can be used as a wildcard.)

In both cases (mapper where, mapper find), if the room is CPK, it will be tagged as such.  (But notice they won't warn you if your destination room isn't CPK, but you have to walk through CPK to reach it.)

* To start walking to a room, type mapper goto followed by the room's id.  This command will only start speedwalks if the destination room is connected to the current room in the map.

First, it will try to find a path from the current room to the destination room.  This process can be slow...  If a path is found, you will start speedwalking.

* Once you're speedwalking to a room, you can stop by typing mapper stop (then continue by typing mapper resume).


To see more details about this plugin, type mapper help.

]],


  ["p7"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p7 ~

[ Example: Adding an abbreviation to a new location, by Jeneya ]

Often we have places we go to several times a day.  Such as a particular reagents shop.

Below is a 1-2-3 on how to create a speedwalk manager abbreviation for getting to Sigil's reagent shop quickly.

We are using the abbreviation "SigReag" to name the shop.  You can name it anything that makes sense to you and doesn't interfere with previous abbreviations.


1. Type "mapper where samantha", without the quotes.

2. Press Enter.

3. Press Ctrl + Alt + Spacebar to go to the Output window.

4. Pres up arrow until you find  "room: Samantha's Source of Power - id: 095BE3E62B0677B387639F5EB1B9B6C80B4BBA93 - area: Sigil"

5. Select the number after id, omit any spaces. Press Ctrl + C to copy it.

6. Press Ctrl + Alt + Spacebar to return to the world window.

7. Type "add abbreviation SigReag 095BE3E62B0677B387639F5EB1B9B6C80B4BBA93 Sigil reagents shop", without the quotes.  (Instead of typing the number, press Ctrl + V to paste it, since we copied it in a previous step.)

8. Press Enter.

If everything goes ok, it will notify you:
-- speedwalk_manager_p2: added abbreviation SigReag to the db --

7. Now anytime you need to speedwalk to Sigil's reagent shop, just type spdn SigReag, and you will start walking to it.

]],


  ["p8"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p8 ~

[ Aliases ]

Aliases can be used to shorten commands, to run a sequence of commands, to name speedwalks, etc.

* To open the aliases window, go to Game, Configure, Aliases (Ctrl + Shift + 9).

This window shows the list of aliases that you have, sorted by group (since the Tree View option is checked.)

* To create a new alias, press Add (Alt + A).  This will open the Edit Alias window.

In the 'Alias' box (Alt + A), type the text you want to use to run the alias.  Use * to replace variable text.  For example, to make an alias named gr for grapple, you would type "gr *", without the enclosing quotes.  The * replaces the target, which is variable.

In the 'Send' box (Alt + S), type the commands you want to run when the alias is executed.  If you're going to run more than one command, type one per line (press Enter after each command).  If your alias has * for variables, to use them here type %%1 for the first *, %%2 for the second, etc.

In the 'Send To' list, choose "world" if your alias will only be using game commands, or "execute" if it will be calling other client aliases, or a combination of client aliases and game commands.  By default, it's set to "execute".

In the 'Group' box (Alt + G), you can type a category name.  This is optional, but helps keep your aliases list less cluttered.

The 'Enabled' box (Alt + E) is checked by default, as it has to be on for the alias to be active.

Aliases are case sensitive by default.  If you want your alias to work no matter if you type it in upper or lower case, check the 'Ignore case' box (Alt + I).

Once done, press 'OK'.


Note: in MUSHclient aliases don't auto-save.  You need to press Ctrl + S if you want to save them.  Aliases added by using this method are saved as part of your world file.

]],


  ["p9"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p9 ~

[ Example: Making an alias to reach a captures notepad, by Jeneya ]

1. Press Ctrl + Shift + 9 to open your aliases window.

2. When you hear "Configuration" and "Aliases" press Alt + A to bring up the alias edit field.  Here is where you will put the shortcut that will bring up your captured notepad so you can look through it.

3. Say we are working on the private notepad where you receive private tells from friends.  I myself use the letters np to note it is a notepad file for private messages.  So I type NP in this edit field.  You can make any alias shortcut that makes sense to you and doesn't interfere with normal stuff on the mud such as typing directions.

4. Press Alt + S to bring up the send edit field.  Here is where you will type "notepad private", without the quotes.

6. Press Alt + G to bring up the group edit field.  I have a group just for channel abbreviations and so I call this channels.  Of course, call it anything that makes sense to you.  Type the name you wish here and press Enter twice.

7. Press Ctrl + S to save your changes.

Now anytime you wish to read your Private messages you can type "np" or whatever abbreviation you made for private tells and read to your heart's content.

When finished just press Ctrl + Alt + Spacebar to go back to the input window.

]],


  ["p10"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p10 ~

[ Aliases, other examples ]

This is an alias that shortens the mapper where command:

1. Press Ctrl + Shift + 9 to open your aliases window.

2. Press Alt + A to add a new alias.

3. Press Alt + A to go to the alias box, then type "mw *", without the quotes.

4. Press Alt + S to go to the send box, then type "mapper where %1", without the quotes.

5. Press Alt + I to check the ignore case box.

6. Press Enter twice to close the dialog windows.

So, when you type "mw church", the alias will execute, calling the mapper where alias, to search for all the rooms named church in your map database.



This is a hide + backstab alias that sends several commands to the world:

1. Press Ctrl + Shift + 9 to open your aliases window.

2. Press Alt + A to add a new alias.

3. Press Alt + A to go to the alias box, then type "bs *", without the quotes.

4. Press Alt + S to go to the send box, then type the following commands, one per line:
remove weapon (press Enter)
wear hook (press Enter)
hide (press Enter)
backstab %1

5. Press Alt + I to check the ignore case box.

6. Press Enter twice to close the dialog windows.

So, when you type "bs pete", the alias will execute, so you will remove your weapon, wear your hook (if there's one in your inventory), hide, then backstab Pete (if he's in your same room.)


In both cases, after testing the aliases, if you decide you want to keep them, press Ctrl + S to save them.

]],


  ["p11"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p11 ~

[ Triggers ]

Triggers make you react automatically to events in the MUD.  (Make sure you read 'help 1879' about Scripts and Botting, to make sure the trigger you want to make is legal in Materia Magica.)

* To open the triggers window, go to Game, Configure, Triggers (Ctrl + Shift + 8).

This window shows the list of triggers that you have, sorted by group (since the Tree View option is checked.)

* To create a new trigger, press Add (Alt + A).  This will open the Edit Trigger window.

In the 'Trigger' box (Alt + T), type or paste the text you want to use to fire the trigger.  Use * to replace variable text.  For example, to make a trigger that reacts when someone pokes you, you would use "* pokes you in the ribs.", without the enclosing quotes.  The * replaces the person's name, which is variable.

In the 'Send' box (Alt + S), type the commands you want to run when the trigger fires.  If you're going to run more than one command, type one per line (press Enter after each command).  If your trigger has * for variables, to use them here type %1 for the first *, %2 for the second, etc.

In the 'Send To' list, choose "world" if your trigger will only be using game commands, or "execute" if it will be calling client aliases, or a combination of client aliases and game commands.  By default, it's set to "execute".

In the 'Group' box (Alt + G), you can type a category name.  This is optional, but helps keep your triggers list less cluttered.

The 'Enabled' (Alt + E) box is checked by default, as it has to be on for the trigger to be active.

The 'Keep evaluating' box (Alt + K) is checked by default, and should always be left checked, in case other triggers match on the same text.  Otherwise, if your trigger happens to fire first, other triggers matching the same text will not work.

Once done, press 'OK'.


Note: in MUSHclient triggers don't auto-save.  You need to press Ctrl + S if you want to save them.  Triggers added by using this method are saved as part of your world file.

]],


  ["p12"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p12 ~

[ Example: Creating a simple SAPI trigger, by Jeneya ]

Sometimes a particular quest asks you to locate a mob and kill him or just rescue him.  I find it nice to use a Trigger to do this with sapi say.  This is what I do to make searching for them easier.  It can also be done with items such as dandelions or wheat or corn stalks.  I even do it for locating heather in the wilds.

1. Press Ctrl + Shift + 8 to open up the triggers configuration page.

2. Press Alt + A to add a new trigger.

3. We are going to look for a beggar so in this field type '*beggar*' without the single quotes.

4. Press Alt + S to go to the send edit field and type "sapi say beggar", without the quotes.

5. Press Alt + I to tell MUSH to ignore case.

6. Press Enter twice to close the dialog windows.

Now you can walk around, or scan for your mob or item.


Once you've located what you were searching for, follow these steps to remove the trigger:

1. Press Ctrl + Shift + 8 to go back to triggers configuration.

2. Press Alt + F to bring up a find field, and type beggar.

3. When it finds it just press Alt + R to remove it.  You will be prompted to say yes that you are wanting to remove one trigger.

4. Press Enter to close the dialog windows.


Actually, when you do a triggers such as the above example, when you go into the configuration menu the last trigger you wrote should be the first trigger in the menu.  I just wanted you to also see how easy searching for either triggers or aliases can be in MUSHclient.

The reason I immediately remove this sort of trigger for mobs is quite simple.  If you leave beggar there it will say beggar every round of fighting in a SAPI voice.

]],


  ["p13"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p13 ~

[ Triggers, other examples ]

This is an example of how to make a trigger that uses SAPI interrupt to say something that requires our immediate attention.  Let's say we're fighting an NPC that instantly slays us if we lose improved invisibility.  We don't want to use SAPI say, because the warning would get queued in the SAPI stream, and we might hear it too late.  So we will use SAPI interrupt instead.

1. Press Ctrl + Shift + 8 to open the triggers window.

2. Press Alt + A to add a new trigger.

3. Press Alt + T to go to the trigger box, then type "You fade back into sight.", without the quotes.  This is the string for losing invisibility.  Ideally, you should select and copy the text from the Output notepad, and paste it in the Trigger box, to make sure that you got it exactly as it appears in the game.

4. Press Alt + S to go to the send box, then type "sapi interrupt invisibility off", without the quotes.

5. Press Alt + I to check the ignore case box.  (This isn't necessary if you copied and pasted the text from the Output notepad.)

6. Press Enter twice to close the dialog windows.

Now whenever we lose invisibility, SAPI will automatically stop whatever it's saying, and warn us about it instead.



This is an example of how to make a trigger to gag something. In this case, we will gag the first error line we get when we mistype a command.  For example, when I type helb, I get this "There is no command 'helb'. You may have meant: help, gclap"

1. Press Ctrl + Shift + 8 to open the triggers window.

2. Press Alt + A to add a new trigger.

3. Press Alt + T to go to the trigger box, then type "There is no command '*'. You may have meant: *", without the double quotes.  Notice I copied this line from my Output notepad, pasted it in the trigger box, and I replced all the parts that can change with asterisks.

4. Press Tab twice to go to the Send to list.  Press Home, it will say World, which is the first option in the list.

5. Press Alt + M to check the Omit from output box.

6. Press Alt + I to check the Ignore case box.  (This isn't necessary if you copied and pasted the text from the Output notepad.)

7. Press Enter twice to close the dialog windows.

Now whenever you mistype a command, that first line suggesting alternative spellings will be gagged.


In both cases, after testing the triggers, if you decide you want to keep them, press Ctrl + S to save them.

]],


  ["p14"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p14 ~

[ Command stacking ]

By default, command stacking is disabled.  To enable it, go to Game, Configure, Commands (Alt + 0), check the 'Command Stacking Using' box (Alt + C), and type the character you want to use in the box to its right.


[ The Commands Sequencer ]

The Sequencer plugin lets you send a list of commands to the world, one at a time, to avoid getting disconnected for spamming.  It is useful for aliases that run a long series of commands, like memorization aliases, aliases that farm reagents or sprigs producers and sort their items into different bags, etc.

After running a command in its list, the Sequencer waits for the next prompt before sending the next command.

* To use the commands sequencer, type sequence commands, followed by the list of commands you want to send to the world, separated by ; (semicolon).

For example:
sequence commands open north;look north

Another example:
sequence commands open mahogany;get all mahogany;close mahogany;put all.sulfur earthen;put all.fish 2.earthen;put all.feather 3.earthen;put all.leaf 4.earthen;put all.sunstone 5.earthen;put all.runestone 6.earthen;drop all.reag

This will make you open your mahogany puzzle box, get everything inside it, close the puzzle box, put all fire reagents into your first earthen bag, all your water reagents into your second earthen bag, etc.  Then it will drop the extra reagents that didn't fit in the bags.


[ Note about your command stacking character and the sequencer ]

* If you're using ; (semicolon) as your command stacking character, whenever you use sequence commands, you will need to write two semicolons instead of one between commands.

For example:
sequence commands open east;;look east

]],


  ["p15"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p15 ~

[ MUD Sound Protocol (MSP) ]

MSP is handled by the msp_lua plugin.  Notice in Materia Magica this protocol requires the MXP protocol to work.  Also, your character needs to set sound on

This bundle includes the Materia Magica sound pack, in MP3 format.  All sound files are located in the MUSHclient/sounds/msp subfolder.

* If you move your MUSHclient installation to another disk or folder, you will need to type msp reset path, so it auto-adjusts to the new location.


[ Other sounds ]

The play_sounds plugin allows you to play sound files from the command window, or from aliases, triggers and timers (by using the send to Execute option.)

Sound files must be placed in the MUSHclient/sounds subfolder, for play_sounds to see them.

* To play a WAV, MP3 or OGG sound file, type play a sound followed by the full file name.  For example, play a sound danger.wav.  Or play a sound msp/mm_knock1.mp3.


The LuaAudio plugin interfaces with the BASS library, which allows us to play several sounds simuntaneously, control sound volume and several other settings.  While this plugin is running, msp_lua and play_sounds will use it automatically.


To see more details about these plugins, type msp_lua help, play_sounds help, and LuaAudio help.

]],


  ["p16"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p16 ~

[ Reading captures without changing focus ]

The read_captures plugin allows you to read your captures without changing focus from the world window.

* To see which captures have unread lines in their queues, type available captures.

* To read the unread lines of a specific type, type read captures followed by a channel type.  For example, read captures clan.

* To clear all lines of a specific type, type purge captures followed by a channel type.  For example, purge captures public.

* To see the list of channel types, type captures list.

* To stop reading the current line, and advance to the next one, type skip line.


To see more details about this plugin, type read_captures help.

]],


  ["p17"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p17 ~

[ Dealing with combat spam: Sbrief ]

To lessen combat spam, we have the Sbrief plugin, which gags most attacks and defenses, and shows totals for each kind instead.

For example, after a normal round of combat, you would get:

The stage illusionist has several minor scratches.
they > acrobatics: 1
they > bash: 1 - fail: 1
me > dodge: 1
me > slash: 3

Notice this isn't the raw output from the MUD, but it's all been rewritten by the Sbrief plugin to make it less spammy.

Also, while Sbrief is connected, and play_sounds is present, you will hear a short sound when the end of a combat round is detected.  This is very useful for timing spells, to help us prevent overcasting.

* To turn these features off, type sbrief off.


To see more details about this plugin, type sbrief help.


]],


  ["p18"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p18 ~

[ Filters for spammy commands ]

The meh_filters plugin lets you check specific data from your score, skills, spells, marks, and personal log, gagging everything else.  It also lets you check specific data from your GMCP char package.

* To list specific info in your score screen, type show score followed by a partial keyword.  For example, show score cc.

* To list specific info in your skills screen, type show skills followed by a partial skill name.  For example, show skills attack.

* To list specific info in your spells screen, type show spells followed by a partial spell name.  For example, show spells cure.

* To list specific info in your marks screen, type show marks followed by a partial mark name.

* To list specific info from your personal log screen, type show log followed by a partial keyword.  For example, show log neverwhen.

* To list specific info from your GMCP char package, type gmcp char followed by a partial group name, and / or a partial property name.  If you specify both a group and a property name, place a . (dot) between them.  For example, gmcp char hunger, or gmcp char thirst.


To see more details about this plugin, type meh_filters help.

]],


  ["p19"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p19 ~

[ The keystrokes manager ]

The accelerators plugin adds the following default keystrokes:

- To walk in a given direction, press the numpad direction.

- To open a door in a given direction, press Ctrl + the numpad direction.

- To look in a given direction, press Alt + the numpad direction.

- To flee in a given direction, press Ctrl + Alt + the numpad direction.

- To flee without a direction, press Ctrl + Alt + numpad 5.


It also lets you handle your own personal keystrokes, from the command window.

Keystrokes send to execute, so you can use them to run both client aliases and game commands.

Keystrokes added by using this plugin will be automatically saved, and reloaded the next time you open the world.

* To toggle all keystrokes on or off, type accel on or off.

* To add a keystroke, type add accel followed by a combination of keys (without spaces), followed by a command or alias.  For example, add accel Alt+F2 peer.

* To remove a keystroke, type del accel followed by a combination of keys (without spaces).  For example, del accel Alt+F2.

* To remove all custom keystrokes, and restore the default ones, type restore default accel.

* To see a list of all keystrokes currently managed by this plugin, type list accel.


To see more details about this plugin, type accelerators help.

]],


  ["p20"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p20 ~

[ Example: Adding a keystroke to stop SAPI speech, by Jeneya ]

You must have the accelerator plugin by Ruthgul in order to make this work.

1. Type add accel Alt+Z sapi stop

2. Press Enter

Now if you get a bunch of SAPI speech and are trying to hear something your reader is saying you just press alt+z and it will stop what SAPI is saying.  You can of course use any combination of keystrokes you wish.

This method will work for most other keystrokes you wish to add.

]],


  ["p21"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p21 ~

[ Example: Adding keystrokes to read your vitals and use the check commands, by Jeneya ]

* Assigning keystrokes for reading your hit points, spell points and stamina with sapi.

It is imperative that we keep track of our own HP, SP and ST.  I use a SAPI voice that is bit different from my regular reader voice so that I take note of the info even in the spammiest situations.

This bundle already includes triggers to read our vitals using the default SAPI voice.  They are gagged from the world window, so our reagular reader voice won't read them.

I assigned Alt + U for my HP, Alt + I for my SP, and Alt + O for my ST.

Below is the example of how I did this for my hit points:

1. Type "add accel Alt+U score hp", without the quotes.

2. Press Enter.

Now every time you press Alt+U, it should read your current HP using your default SAPI voice.


Now do this with the other score commands so you have this important info at your fingertips.


* Assigning keystrokes for the check commands

Recently the 'check commands' became available to us on MM.  These are awesome commands, but often we are in the middle of battle when we need to check the important info they give us, and typing out the whole command is just not possible if we wish to stay alive ourselves, or keep the tank or another form member alive.

These are some of the most useful check commands:

check victim - returns your current target's name
check victimhp - returns your current target's health %
check lowest - returns the weakest formation member's name and health %
check tank - lists formation members and their health percent who are currently targeted

I use Alt + M for check victim, Alt + , (comma) for check victimhp,
Alt + . (period) for check lowest, and Alt + / (slash) for check tank.

Proceed as in the previous example to add accelerator for these very important commnds.

]],


  ["p22"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p22 ~

[ Example: Adding a keystroke to read captures without leaving the world window, by Jeneya ]

I like to read my capture channels on the fly while staying in my main window.  I find this to be the best option especially when in a form fighting.  I also like to keep up on clan talk and my private tells while sometimes walking or fighting.   "Read Captures" is a wonderful way to accomplish this.

I chose the keys J K and L for private messages, clan talk and form talk respectively.  I chose to pair them with the Alt key.  So Alt + J reads my private tells, and Alt + K reads my clan messages, and Alt + L reads my form messages.  You can use any keystroke combinations that work for you.  Below is how I did this.

1. Install "read_captures" plugin.  Also you need to have accelerators plug in installed and all plugins associated with both of them.

2. Type the following - add accel Alt+J read captures notepad private

3. Press Enter.

4. Now just wait for a tell message and press Alt+J to read it quickly without changing to output window or to notepad private.

You can add keystrokes following the same procedure for clan (Alt+K) and form (Alt+L) messages.

]],


  ["p23"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p23 ~

[ Making aliases that work with and without a target ]

The addalias alias lets you create simple aliases that will work both with and without a target.

* To add an alias using this feature, type addalias, followed by the name you want for the alias (it can't contain spaces), followed by the game command, game alias, or client alias you want it to execute.


For example: addalias b bash

Then, once you've added it:
b goblin - will bash a goblin (if there's one in your room.)
b - will bash your current opponent in combat.
b south - will bash the south oor (if there is one)


Another example: addalias md cast 'magic dart'

Then, once you've added it:
md 'short rogue' - will cast magic dart on a short rogue (if there's one in your room.)
md - will cast magic dart on your current opponent in combat.

]],


  ["p24"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p24 ~

[ How to install a plugin ]

This bundle includes several plugins, split in 2 folders:

- Those plugins that come with the original MUSHclient installer, are in the MUSHclient/worlds/plugins/ folder.

- Those plugins that we added to the package, which might specific for Materia Magica or not, are in the MUSHclient/worlds/plugins/MM/ folder.


To install a plugin, follow these steps:

1. Press Ctrl + Shift + P to open your plugins window.

2. Press Alt + A to open the ad plugin window.  It will show you the list of files in the plugins folder.

3. If the plugin you're going to add is specific for this package, then open the "MM" folder.

4. Select the plugin you want to install in the list of files.

5. Press Alt + O to open it.

6. Press Alt + C to close the plugins window.

7. Press Ctrl + S to save the changes.


[ How to uninstall a plugin ]

To uninstall a plugin, follow these steps:

1. Press Ctrl + Shift + P to open your plugins window.

2. Select the plugin you want to uninstall.

3. Press Alt + R to remove the plugin.

4. Press Alt + C to close the plugins window.

5. Press Ctrl + S to save the changes.

]],


  ["p25"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p25 ~

[ How to update a plugin ]

This bundle includes the plugins_updater plugin, which lets you update the other plugins you have installed by typing a few aliases.

For example, to update the gmcp mapper plugin.

1. Type "update plugin mapper", without the quotes.

2. As a result, you will get this output:
* MM_GMCP_Mapper_GMCP (by Nick Gammon, Ruthgul):
update plugin f973af093e715dece34dc25f
update aux f973af093e715dece34dc25f

3. Type "notepad output" without the quotes, to go to the Output notepad, select and copy the line that says "update aux f973af093e715dece34dc25f".

4. Press Ctrl + Alt + Spacebar, to return to your world window, paste what you just copied, and press Enter.  Wait for it to finish donwloading.

5. Again, type "notepad output" without the quotes, to go to the Output notepad, and this time select and copy the line that says "update plugin f973af093e715dece34dc25f".

6. And once again, press Ctrl + Alt + Spacebar, to return to your world window, paste what you just copied, and press Enter.  Wait for it to finish downloading.

If everything went ok, the plugin will now be updated.


In this case, the plugin has an auxiliary file, and that's why you had to copy / paste 2 separate commands.  Most other plugins don't have auxiliary files, so they are fully updated by just entering the "update plugin <id>" command.


To see more details about this plugin, type plugins_updater help.

]],


  ["p26"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p26 ~

[ Macro keystrokes and output ]

control shift c	clear output
control shift o	next line
control alt enter - toggle interrupt
control alt o	toggle output
control shift I	current line
control shift space - select
control shift U	previous line
control shift N	end line
control shift Y	top line
control shift S	snapshot

alt U	reads your health percent
alt I	reads your spell point percent
alt O	reads your stamina percent
alt J	reads last 5 messages
alt K	reads last 5 clan messages
alt L	reads last 5 form talks
alt R	reads last 5 VI relays
alt A	reads 5 last alliance talk
alt ;	reads 5 last says
alt P	reads 5 last announcements
alt '	reads last auctions
alt C	reads compass coordinates
alt ,	victim's health percent
alt .	reads health percent of lowest health form member
alt /	reads health and name of current tank

control F12	toggle sound
control shift F12	TTS (toggle?)
numberpad 5	(while on transport item - stand)


[ Numberpad and directions ]

control <numberpad> will open that direction
alt <numberpad>	will look that direction
control alt <numberpad>	will flee that direction

]],

  ["p27"] = [[

~ MUSHclient Bundle for Materia Magica, p27 ~

[ Pre-installed plugins and features ]

* Pre-installed plugins; Accelerators, Bazaar Walk, Capture2dworld, Capture2notepads, Detect Globals, Faux Sextant, Global Vars, Lua Audio, Meh Filters, Meh Prompt VI, MM GMCP handler, MM GMCP Mapper, MSP Lua, MushReader, Output Functions, Play Sounds, Plugins Updater, Read Captures, Repeat Command, SAPI speaker, SBrief, Sequencer, Speedwalk Manager GMCP P2, this set of lessons.

* MSP Sound pack for Materia Magica (MP3 format).

* BASS library, which allows MUSHclient to play several sound files simultaneously.

* Generic aliases: addalias, enable group, disable group.

* SAPI triggers for some check commands.

* Pseudo-roads to get to most locations in Sigil Underground.


[ Other plugins, included in the bundle but not pre-installed ]

* Affects by Name, Bank Helper, Crystal Locator, Eq Slots, Generic Buy, Kills TNL, Latest Daily, Meh Id, Meh Pirates, Meh Timers, Mems Helper, Missing Affects, Quests, Reagents Buy, Ship KP, Ship Lookout, Tick, Trace_to_Notepad, Transport KP


Of these other plugins, you may wanna take a look at the following:

- meh_id, which names most scrolls, sprigs, mixes, Pendant of Lord Maldra lights, and surveyed locations; shows open worldgates, and Wandering Sidhe location;

- ship_kp and transport_kp, which let you control your ship or your transportation item (broom, rocking horse, magic carpet, etc.) using your numeric keypad;

- tick, which will play a short sound 3 seconds before a game tick (HP, SP, ST regeneration happens on tick);

- Trace_to_Notepad, which sends the Trace output to a notepad window, to prevent it from spamming the main world window.  This can very useful to help diagnose a rogue trigger, timer, etc.

]],


}



----------------
-- show a page
----------------

function show_a_page(page)
  if (page) then
    ColourNote("silver", "black", page)
  end
end


]]>

</script>

</muclient>
